Guide to the Rose Rand Papers, 1903-1981 ASP.1990.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Rose Rand Papers
1903-1981
1926-1980
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Rand, Rose
ASP.1990.01
18.75 Linear Feet
Rose Rand was a student member of the Vienna Circle, a group of philosophers who met on a regular basis for discussions in Vienna, Austria, from 1922 to 1938, and who proposed new philosophical ideas about the conception of scientific knowledge. The papers comprise Rose Rand's personal and professional records, a significant amount of correspondence and working papers, as well as notebooks, research notes, manuscript fragments, and transcriptions from Vienna Circle discussions. They also include 48 annotated books from her personal library. Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Arrangement
Series I. Personal and Financial Records
Series II. Educational and Professional Records
Series III. Rose Rand's Personal and Professional Correspondence
Series IV. Translations and Original Works by Rose Rand
Series V: Writings by Other Authors
Series VI: Rose Rand's Research Notes, Transcriptions, Manuscript Fragements, and Minutes
Series VII: Rose Rand's Notebooks and Papers by Other Authors
Series VIII: Annotated Books from Rose Rand's Library
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Biography
Rose Rand studied philosophy at the University of Vienna from 1924-1928. Among her teachers were Robert Reininger, Heinrich Gomperz, Moritz Schlick, and Rudolf Carnap. After her graduation in 1928 and during her time as a PhD candidate, she stayed in close intellectual contact with Schlick and other members of the Vienna Circle. She participated at Vienna Circle meetings, mainly through the years 1930-1935, and recorded several of the discussions in the form of minutes. Rose Rand received her doctorate in philosophy from the University of Vienna in 1938 with a dissertation on "T. Kotarbinski's Philosophy."
In 1939 Rose Rand left Austria and emigrated to England where she attended the seminars of Ludwig Wittgenstein at Cambridge University. She received a small research grant in 1950 and was able to go to Oxford University as a "recognized student." Rose Rand emigrated to the United States in 1954. From May 1954 until September 1955, she attempted to pursue her research, using the libraries at Princeton and Harvard universities, while searching for academic employment. During the years 1955 to 1959 she held temporary teaching positions at the University of Chicago (elementary mathematics), at the University of Indiana at Gary (ancient philosophy and logic), and as a research associate at Notre Dame University. At the beginning of 1959, Rose Rand returned to Cambridge, MA, and later to Princeton, NJ. During the years that followed until her death in 1980 her main source of income consisted of various grants and fellowships, mainly for her translations of Polish and Russian logicians. When not backed by such support, she depended on private loans and other financial assistance, free-lance translation work, or sporadic temporary employment. Rose Rand died on July 28, 1980 in Princeton, NJ, at the age of 77.
Scope and Content Notes
The papers comprise her personal and professional records, a significant amount of correspondence and working papers, as well as notebooks, research notes, manuscript fragments, and transcriptions from Vienna Circle discussions. They also include annotated books from her personal library. The personal and professional records cover items such as legal and educational documents, testimonials, financial and health care records, as well as photographs, travel documents, and address books. Her working papers, manuscripts, transcriptions, and note books record largely her work as a translator, her own research, and discussions and presentations from the Vienna Circle. The correspondence is extensive, more than 1600 letters, and covers a wide range of dates, from the early period in Vienna to the time right after her death. Correspondents include prominent members of the Vienna Circle and affiliated individuals, such as Rudolf Carnap, Moritz Schlick, Otto Neurath, Ludwig Wittgenstein, and Karl Popper. Covered are also exchanges with the Polish philosophers Tadeusz Kotarbinski, Kazimierz Ajdukiewicz, and Alfred Tarski, with family and friends, and numerous institutions. The books from her library are all annotated and amount to 48 volumes. Their topics concern mostly philosophy of science and logic. They are stored in two Paige boxes together with the manuscript collection.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers were received in one accession on June 4, 1990 from the administrator of the Rose Rand estate, James R. Alt.
Previous Citation
Rose Rand Papers, 1903-1981, ASP.1990.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Science -- Philosophy -- History -- Sources; Science -- Philosophy -- History -- 20th century; Vienna circle; Women philosophers; Jewish women philosophers; Philosophy; Logical positivism -- History -- 20th century; Wittgenstein, Ludwig; Kotarbinski, Tadeusz; Lesniewski, Stanislaw; Rand, Rose; Schlick, Moritz; Tarski, Alfred; Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970; Ajdukiewicz, Kazimierz
- Personal and Financial Records, 1903-1981; I.
  Scope and Contents note
  Rose Rand's personal and financial records contain bank statements, legal documents, receipts, tax, health care, and travel documents, several address books, and photographs. Included are her birth certificate, forms and communications concerning immigration to the U.S. and naturalization, and affidavits of support. Correspondence covers health, legal, and housing issues, and financial assistance. Items in the last two folders of this series concern transactions after her death such as funeral arrangements and establishment of a memorial book fund in her name at Princeton University Library.
  - Legal Documents, 1903-1980 and undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Earnings Statements and Income Documentation, 1950-1970 and undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bank Accounts: Cambridge Trust Company, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bank Accounts: Princeton Bank and Trust Company, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bank Accounts: Princeton Bank and Trust Company, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bank Accounts: Princeton Bank and Trust Company, 1963-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bank Accounts: Princeton Bank and Trust Company: Miscellaneous Transactions, 1965-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bank Accounts: Princeton Bank and Trust Company: Promissory notes, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bank Accounts: Oxford and Chicago, 1956-1958 and undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Receipts: Books and Photocopies, 1950-1978 and undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Receipts: Various Personal Expenditures and Related Correspondence, 1951-1974 and undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tax Documents and Related Correspondence, 1955-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Housing and Related Correspondence, 1952-1979 and undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Moving and Storage and Related Correspondence, 1955-1973 and undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Health Care Documents and Related Correspondence, 1936-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Social Security, Benefits, Social Services, and Related Correspondence, 1955-1980 and undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Legal Actions and Damage Claims and Related Correspondence, 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence on Library Access Problems, 1957-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Travel Ephemera, 1926-1936 and undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Travel Documents, 1954-1977 and undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Address Books, Professional/Institutional, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Address Books, Personal and Professional, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Address and Note Books, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Loose Address Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Photographs: Rose Rand, Family, and Unidentified, 1918-1980 and undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous and Unidentified (includes photo of Ludwig Wittgenstein), 1920-1946 and undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Various Personal Documents and Notes, 1924-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Post-Mortem Documents and Correspondence, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Post-Mortem: Rose Rand Book Fund, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Educational and Professional Records, 1912-1979; II.
  This series contains several versions of Rose Rand's curriculum vitae, certificates and diplomas, including early grade reports in Polish, Russian, and German from Lwow and Vienna, and her student record book and exam certificates from the University of Vienna. Also featured are lists of her publications, letters of recommendation written for her, and extensive correspondence regarding applications for fellowhips and grants with the National Science Foundation. In addition, there are exchanges with Polish logicians such as Tadeusz Kotarbinksi, Kazimierz Ajdukiewicz, and Alfred Tarski, as well as with various Polish institutions.
  - Rose Rand's Curricula Vitae, 1959-1978 and undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lists of Publications by Rose Rand, 1965, 1969, and undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Educational Certificates and Diplomas, 1912-1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Report Card in Polish, 1912; 1.
    - Report Card in Polish, 1914; 2.
    - Report Card in Polish, 1917; 3.
    - Report Card in Polish, 1918; 4.
    - Report Card in Russian, 1919; 5.
    - Report Card in Polish, 1919; 6.
    - Report Card in Polish, 1919; 7.
    - Report Card in German, 1923; 8.
    - Report Card in German, 1923; 9.
    - Report Card in German, 1923; 10.
    - High-School Diploma, 1924; 11.
    - Report Card in German, 1924; 12.
    - Report Card School for Stenography, 1924; 13.
    - Diploma School for Stenography, 1924; 14.
    - Meldungsbuch, University of Vienna, 1924-1928; 15.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1924-1925; 16.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1924-1925; 17.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1925; 18.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1925; 19.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1925; 20.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1926; 21.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1926; 22.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1927; 23.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1927; 24.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1927; 25.
    - Report Card University of Vienna, 1932; 26.
    - Absolutorium University of Vienna, 1937; 27.
    - Dissertation Approval, 1937; 28.
    - Certificate of Doctoral Viva in Philosophy, University of Vienna, 1937; 29.
    - Certificate of Doctoral Viva in Physics, University of Vienna, 1938; 30.
    - Certificate of Habilitation in Philosophy, University of Vienna, 1938; 31.
    - Diploma of Dissertation in Philosphy, University of Vienna, 1938 and 1939; 32.
    - Certificate of Auswanderungsabteilung der Israelischen Kultusgemeinde, 1939; 33.
    - Certifcate of Admission Student-at-Large, University of Chicago, 1956; 34.
  - Educational Correspondence, 1940-1956 and undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation and Testimonials, 1934-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fellowship and Grant Correspondence: A-B, 1959-1979 and undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fellowship and Grant Correspondence: C-N, 1945-1978 and undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fellowship and Grant Correspondence: P-Z, Mulit-Institutional, and Unidentified, 1939-1979 and undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - National Science Foundation Correspondence, 1956-1961 and undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - National Science Foundation Correspondence, 1962-1963 and undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - National Science Foundation Correspondence, 1964-1979 and undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Programs: Symposia, Conventions, and Conferences, 1956-1976 and undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Course Material on Physics and Mathematics, 1956-1957 and undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Polish, Individuals, A-KA, 1936-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Polish, Kotarbinski, 1936-1979 and undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Polish, Individuals, KR-Z and Unidentified, 1956-1973 and undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Polish, Institutions, A-Z, 1938-1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Rose Rand's Personal and Professional Correspondence, 1924-1980; III.
  The majority of the correspondence is divided into two categories, personal and professional correspondence. The category "personal correspondence" covers mostly private topics, such as finance, health, or issues relating to family and friends. The category "professional correspondence" comprises topics such as research, publications, employment, or grants. Among the correspondents are Ina and Rudolf Carnap, Herbert Feigl, Carl G. Hempel, Viktor Kraft, Herta Leng, Heinz Neider, Otto Neurath, Karl Popper, Moritz Schlick, Susan Stebbing, Gregory Vlastos, and Ludwig Wittgenstein. Exchanges with institutions include Fonds zur Hilfeleistung an politisch Verfolgte (Vienna), Institute for Advanced Study, and Princeton University.
  - Personal Correspondence: Individuals, A-D, 1931-1980 and undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: Individuals, E-H, 1926-1980 and undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence: Individuals, K-N, 1931-1980 and undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence: Individuals, P-R, 1924-1979 and undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence: Individuals, S-V, 1935-1980 and undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence: Individuals, W-Z and Unidentified, 1927-1980 and undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence: Institutions, A-Z and Unidentified, 1951-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General Professional Correspondence: Individuals, A-B, 1931-1977 and undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Professional Correspondence: Individuals, C, 1932-1979 and undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General Professional Correspondence: Individuals, D-K, 1934-1974 and undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Professional Correspondence: Individuals, L-N, 1925-1979 and undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Professional Correspondence: Individuals, P-S, 1932-1979 and undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Professional Correspondence: Individuals, T-Z and Unidentified, 1939-1973 and undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Professional and Personal Correspondence: Individuals, Ludwig Wittgenstein, 1941-1946 and undated (Box 3, Folder 13A)
  - General Professional Correspondence: Institutions, A-Z and Unidentified, 1941-1978 and undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Employment Correspondence, 1940-1957 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Employment Correspondence, 1958-1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Employment Correspondence, 1968-1974 and undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Publishing Correspondence: Institutions, A-M, 1938-1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Publishing Correspondence: Institutions, N-Z and Unidentified, 1939-1976 and undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Professional Associations, 1956-1967 and undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Translations and Original Works by Rose Rand, 1936-1978; IV.
  Included in this series are Rose Rand's typed and handwritten drafts of her English translations of the works of Polish logicians such as Stanislaw Lesniewski and Jan Lukasiewicz, a translation of Paul Lorenzen's Einführung in die operative Logik und Mathematik, several translations of works by Gottlob Frege, and some of Rose Rand's own writings. The authors and titles of Rose Rand's translations appear first in the folder heading. The original title of the translation follows in italics and enclosed in square brackets.
  - Kazimierz Ajdukiewicz: Elementary Logic [Zarys logiki], undated (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Kazimierz Ajdukiewicz: Various Writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Leon Chwistek: Various Writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gottlob Frege: Various Writings, 1961 and undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Roman Ingarden and Zbigniew Jordan: About the Conditional and On Determinism, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Tadeusz Kotarbinski: Tractatus about Efficient Work [Tractato o dobrej robocie], 1960 and undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tadeusz Kotarbinski: Textbook of logic for Lawyers [Kurs logiki dla Prawnikow], undated (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
  - Tadeusz Kotarbinski, Kasimierz Kuratowski, and I.A. Lavrov: Various Writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: Various Writings, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: About the Foundations of Mathematics and Über die Grundlagen der Mathematik [O Podstawach Matematyki], 1939, 1958, and undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: About the Foundations of Mathematics [O Podstawach Matematyki], Parts 4 and 5, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: About the Foundations of Mathematics [O Podstawach Matematyki], Parts 6 through 11, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: Warious Writings, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: Introductory Remarks to the Continuation of My Communication with the Title: 'An Outline of a New System of the Foundations of Mathematics' [Einleitende Bemerkungen zur Fortsetzung meiner Mitteilung u.d. T. "Grundzüge eines neuen Systems der Grundlagen der Mathematik"], undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: About the Outline of a New System on the Foundation of Mathematics [Grundzüge eines neuen Systems der Grundlagen der Mathematik], undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: Outline About a New System About the Foundations of Mathematics [Grundzüge eines neuen Systems der Grundlagen der Mathematik], undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: Various Writings, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Stanislaw Lesniewski: Critique of the Law of the Excluded Middle [Krytyka logicznej zasady wylaczonego srodka], 1964 and undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Paul Lorenzen: Introduction to Operative Logic and Mathematics [Einführung in die operative Logik und Mathematik], undated (Box 5, Folder 11-14)
  - Paul Lorenzen: Introduction to Operative Logic and Mathematics [Einführung in die operative Logik und Mathematik], undated (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  - Jan Lukasiewicz: Various Writings, undated (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Jan Lukasiewicz: About the Priniciple of Contradiction in Aristotle [O zasadzie sprezecznosci u Arystotelesa], 1961 and undated (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
  - Jan Lukasiewicz: The Logical Foundations of the Probability-Calculus [Die logischen Grundlagen der Wahrscheinlichkeitsrechnung], 1962 and undated (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Jan Lukasiewicz: Various Writings, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Jan Lukasiewicz: Philosophical Remarks on the Multi-Valued Systems of the Calculus of Propositions [Uwagi filozoficzne o wielowartosciowych systemaach rachunku zdan], 1962, 1964, and undated (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Jan Lukasiewicz, Alfred Tarski, I.I. Peschkova, Ryszard Przybylski: Various Writings, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Viktor Stern, Alfred Tarski, Nikolai A. Vasil'ev: Various Writings, 1937 and undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Nikolai A. Vasil'ev: Imaginary Non-Aristotelian Logic, 1967 and undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Nikolai A. Vasil'ev: Logic and Metalogic, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Rose Rand: Die Logik der verschiedenen Arten von Sätzen and Logic of the Different Kinds of Sentences, 1936, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rose Rand: Philosophenkongress in Krakau, Dissertation on T. Kotarbinski's Philosophie, September 1936, 1937-1938, and undated (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Rose Rand: Die Begriffe 'wirklich', 'nichtwirklich' auf Grund der Befragung Geisteskranker and A Study of the Notions 'Real' and 'Unreal' Based on the Questioning of Mental Patients, 1938, 1941, 1951, and undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Rose Rand: A Study of the Notions 'Real', 'Unreal' Based on the Questioning of Mental Patients and Logik der Forderungen, 1938, 1939, 1941, 1963, 1967, 1969, and undated (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Rose Rand: Logik der Forderungssätze and The Logic of Demand Sentences, 1939, 1950, and undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Rose Rand: The Logic of Demand Sentences, 1939, 1947, 1962, and undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Rose Rand: Reviews of Works by Roman Ingarden and Tadeusz Kotarbinski and her Lecture The Influence of Wittgenstein's Philosophy on the Viennese Circle and on the Oxford School of Analytic Philosophy, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Rose Rand: The Influence of Wittgenstein's Philosophy on the Viennese Circle and on the Oxford School of Analytic Philosophy, 1962 and undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Rose Rand: Review of Jerzy Slupecki's Edition of Jan Lukasiewicz's Papers On Problems of Logic and Philosophy [Z zagadnien logiki i filozofii ], 1966, 1968, and undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Rose Rand: Prolegomena to Three-Valued Logic, 1964-1968, and undated (Box 8, Folder 4-10)
  - Rose Rand: "The Law of Contradiction in Aristotle" (O ZASADZIE SPRZECZNOSCI U ARYSTOTELESA) BY JAN ŁUKASIEWICZ, 1975, 1978, and undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Writings by Other Authors, 1912-1979; V.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Scope Note: This series comprises writings by other authors in form of congress lectures, annotated journal articles and selections of books in English, German, and Polish; or entire issues of journals that Rose Rand apparently used heavily for her own research and study.
  - Inter-American Congress of Philosophy, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
  - Annotated Photocopies, Authors A-LE, 1912-1913, 1973, 1979, and undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Annotated Photocopies, Authors N-Z, 1912-1913, 1963, 1965, and undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Annotated Journal Articles, 1921-1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Annotated Journal Articles, 1928, 1965, and 1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Tadeusz Kotarbinski: Annotated Article Reprints, 1918-1947 and undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Article Reprints, 1930-1937 and undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Rudolf Carnap: Annotated Article Reprints, 1931-1935 and undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Rudolf Carnap: Annotated Article Reprints, 1931-1945 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Annotated Article Reprints and Journal Issues: Authors A-J, 1933-1979 and undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Annotated Article Reprints and Journal Issues: Authors K-S, 1931-1973 and undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Annotated Article Reprints and Journal Issues: Authors R-Z, 1928-1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Moritz Schlick, Gesammelte Aufsätze, 1930-1938 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
- Rose Rand's Research Notes, Transcriptions, Manuscript Fragements, and Minutes, 1912-1978; VI.
  Featured in this series are reading notes and summaries in English and German on works by different authors, organized alphabetically by each author's last name. Included are also Rose Rand's typed minutes of Vienna Circle meetings and transcriptions of circle presentations with handwritten annotations in German and German shorthand, mostly contained in folder 10-9 and 11-9, but some related documents can also be found in folder 10-13 and 10-15. Folders 11-6 entitled "Wirklichkeit" and 11-15 contain, among others, shorthand notes on lectures by Wittgenstein and typescripts entitled "Wittgenstein at home" and "Diskussion zwischen Wittgenstein und mir."
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors A-B (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Rudolf Carnap, 1932 and undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors Ca-Höl, 1937 and undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Vincent Hope, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors Hu-J, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Minutes and Transcriptions from the Vienna Circle, 1931 and undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors Kau-La, 1952 and undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors Le-Lu, 1965, 1966, and undated (Box 10, Folder 11)